A Guide to the Rebecca C. Lancefield papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA173
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rebecca C. Lancefield papers, Rockefeller University Faculty
undated
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University
Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
Lancefield, Rebecca Craighill
FA173
22 Cubic Feet 27 boxes
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be closed to research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment
Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be closed to researchers at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/Head of Reference.
Biographical/Historical note
Rebecca Craighill Lancefield, researcher in bacteriology at The Rockefeller University from 1925 worked on immunochemical studies of streptococci and the chemical composition and antigenic structure of hemolytic streptococci. Her classification system of hemolytic streptococci, known universally as The Lancefield Group, has served to illuminate the biology of these organisms and the mechanisms by which they produce disease.
Biographical note
1895 Born January 5, Ft. Wadsworth, New York
1916 A.B. Wellesley College, Wellesley, Massachusetts
1918 A.M. Columbia University, New York, N.Y.
1918-1919 Technical assistant, The Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research, NYC
1919-1921 Carnegie Inst. Staff of exp. evolution Department of Genetics
1921-1922 University of Oregon. Instructor in bacteriology
1922-1925 Technical assistant, RIMR, New York, N.Y.
1925 Ph. D. (Immunology, bacteriology) Columbia University
1925-1929 Assistant, RIMR
1929-1942 Associate, RIMR
1942-1958 Associate Member, RIMR
1944 Civilian with Office of Scientific Research and Development, U.S. Government
1958-1965 Member/Professor Microbiology Rockefeller University
1960 T. Duckett Jones Medal (Helen Hay Whitney Found.)
1964 Gehrmann lecturer, Illinois College of Medicine
1965 Professor Emeritus, Rockefeller University
1964 Achievement Award, American Heart Association
1971 Modern Medicine Award for distinguished achievement
1972 Wellesley Achievement Award (Wellesley College Alumnae)
1973 New York Academy of Medicine Medal
1973 D. Sc. (Honorary) Rockefeller University
Member of: National Academy of Sciences, AAAS, American Society of Microbiology (Vice-president 1942; president 1943, honorary member), American Association of Immunology (President 1961-1962), Pathological Society of Great Britain & Ireland (honorary). American Public Health Association, Harvey Society.
Scope and Contents note
Biographical materials, bibliography, photographs, correspondence, laboratory notes, and other materials.
File Plan note
Former Classification: I 450 L221
Conditions Governing Access note
This collection is open for research.
Medical sciences; Life sciences; Diseases; Streptococcus; Immunology; Bacteriology; Bacteria; Medical education; Medical research; Chemistry; Cell and biomolecular sciences; Biology -- Research; Biochemistry; Prevention and health; Medicine, Preventive; Rockefeller University; Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research; Lancefield, Rebecca Craighill
- Biographical material, photographs, award announcements (Box 1)
- Reprints (Box 1)
- Laboratory notebooks
  - Methods of making streptococcus antigens, 1922 November 1-1923 December 28 (Box 1)
  - Complement fixation tests, 1922 December 14-1923 1922 December 28-1925 January 6 (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents note
    Includes reading notes and miscellaneous items which are not in place but transcribed for comparisons.
  - Stock antiformic antigens Used for testing patient sera, 1922 December 28-1923 March 13 (Box 1)
  - Nucleo-protein antigens (Antigen B) Dr. Avery's method, 1923 March 19-1923 July 1 (Box 1)
  - Nucleo-protein antigens (Antigen B) Stock antiformic antigens, 1923 September 25-1925 January 6 (Box 1)
  - Rabbit series. Immunity curves; precipitations; agglutinations, 1923-1925 (Box 1)
  - Complement fixation tests. Original records on patient sera and exudates, 1923-1925 (Box 1)
  - Absorption experiments/Extraction methods, 1923-1925 (Box 1)
  - Non hemolytic streptococcus. S and P titrations Papers of July 1925, 1924-1925 (Box 2)
  - Test bleeding and titrations (Rabbit), 1925-1927 (Box 2)
  - Rabbit series: S43; C23; S23; London series Agglutinations, active immunity, absorption, 1927-1928 (Box 2)
  - Scarlet strains/ Test bleeding on rabbit Rb passage culture, 1927-1928 (Box 2)
  - Strains under study for antigenic relationships, 1942-1943 (Box 2)
  - Culture book as per series (Box 2)
  - Culture book as per group type (Box 2)
  - Group A - summary of types, 1942-1943 (Box 2)
  - Reports Group A strains untyped. A.A.F., 1944 (Box 2)
    Includes letters forwarding and explaining conditions of samples.
  - A.A.F. Report on typing streptococci, 1944 (Box 2)
- Correspondence
  - Griffith, Fred, 1935-1937 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Typing charts, methods, and procedures (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence re contaminated, unreliable, or incorrect cultures, circa 1950-1971 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Arrangement note
    [originally was in chronological groups; rearranged by mistake] Note: [Remaining files in chronological groups, alphabetized within groups].
  - Aksungur, Pauline, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Alexian Brothers Hospital, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Allen, James C., 1960 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Allison, Fred. Jr., 1960 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Allison, V.D., 1947 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Amano, T., 1954 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - American Heart Association, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Anderson, Harold C., 1950-1970 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Annual Review of Microbiology, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - American Type Culture Collection, 1950-1961 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Anthony, Bascom F., 1967-1979 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Applied Microbiology, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Armstrong, Alan S., 1967-1969 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Armstrong, Charles H., 1964 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Armstrong, Philip B., 1959 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Aronson, M., 1957 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Arvidson, Mai, 1954 1957 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Avery, Roy, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Ayres, Harry Morgan, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Armed Forces Epidemiological Board, 1955-1977 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Austrian, Robert, 1951-1973 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Ayoub, Elia, 1965-1976 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Baer, Harold, 1947-1951 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Bancroft, Paul M., 1947 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Barnett, Charles P., 1950 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Barreto, J.B., 1948 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Barry, Guy T., 1960 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Bazeley, P.L., 1949 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Beeuwkes, H., 1949 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Berglund, H., 1947 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Bernhard, William G., 1947-1950 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Bernheimer, Alan W., 1948 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Birkeland, Jorgen M., 1950 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Blatt, Hermann, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Blevins, Anne, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Böhmig, R., 1947 1949 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Boyd, William C., 1959 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Boyden, Stephen V., 1950 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Breckenridge, R.L., 1954 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Brenes, Mario, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Brooke, Marcus, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Brunner, M.J., 1947 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Buonomini, G., 1947 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Baker, Hinton J., 1958 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Baldwin, Virginia, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Baram, Peter, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - de Barjacoba, Francisca De Toma, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Barkulis, S.S., 1953-1955 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Barnes, Ella M., 1958 1959 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Barrow, Jack, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Bauer, Walter, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Bearn, Alexander, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Bekker, J.H., 1954-1956 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Bernheimer, Alan W., 1961 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Bernstein, Stanley H., 1956-1961 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Beveridge, W.I.B., 1959 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Bland, N., 1959 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Blumgart, Herrman L., 1956 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Boehmig, R., 1956 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Boissard, J., 1959 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Boyd, William C., 1954 1959 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Braude, A.I., 1954 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Brunner, A.E., 1959 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Bryan, John S., 1955 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Bryson, Vernon, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Burnett, George W., 1961 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Bynoe, E.T., 1958 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Baker, Carol J., 1971-1973 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Balows, Albert, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - de Barjacoba, Francisca, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Barkulis, S.S., 1965 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Barnes, Ella M., 1962 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Bazin, H., 1972 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Beachey, Edwin H., 1973 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Becker, Carl, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Bennett, H. Stanley, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Bernstein, Stanley H., 1962-1967 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Berry, Ira R., 1963 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Beskid, George, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Bisno, Alan L., 1970 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Black, David G. Jr., 1973 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Bland, Nadia, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Bleiweis, Arnold S., 1964 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Bond, V.P., 1963 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Breese, Burtis B., 1967 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Buettner, Louis E., 1962 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Bynoe, E.T., 1963 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Baker, Carol J., 1973-1978 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Balows, Albert, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Battisto, Jack R., 1978 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Blevins, Anne, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Block, Earl F., 1975 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Blum, Paul M., 1980 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Bodnar, Andrew G., 1976 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Botta, Giuseppe A., 1978 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Bowers, John Z., 1974 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Braun, Dietmar G., 1976 1979 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Britton, Gary, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Brown, George L., 1975 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Bruno, Pauline, 1974-1977 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Camara, Antonio Alves Jr., 1954 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Canaperia, Giovanni A., 1950 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Catanzaro, Francis J., 1954 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Chapman, Earle M., 1950 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Cheve, Jean, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Christopher, W.N., 1949 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Cinander, B., 1953 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Ciuca, M., 1948-1949 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Cluff, Leighton E., 1954 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Coburn, Alvin F., 1947-1953 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Coffey, Julia M., 1947-1954 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Cohn, Alfred, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Colburn, Charles G., 1952 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Cordle, Frank, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Cotoni, L., 1948 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Cox, Marcus E., 1948 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Crowley, Nuala, 1947-1951 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Curnen, Edward C., 1950-1952 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Campbell, Berry, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Caravano, René, 1956-1963 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Casellas, José M., 1966 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Chapman, S.S., 1964-1967 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Cheever, F.S., 1957 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Clark, W.A., 1964 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Cluff, Leighton E., 1959-1960 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Cole, Leon R., 1955 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Cole, Roger M., 1959-1960 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Colebrook, Leonard, December 21 [year illegible] (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Cook, Charles D., 1966 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Cox, Marcus E., 1955 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Crowley, Nuala, 1957-1959 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Cruthchley, M.J., 1958 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Cummins, Cecil S., 1958-1961 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Curtin, James A., 1959 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Campbell, Charlotte C., 1975 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Cantor, Ena D., 1970 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Carp, Richard I., 1972 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Carrada-Bravo, T., 1972 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Chapman, S. Stephen, 1968-1970 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Chase, Randolph, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Chawla, N.P.S., 1974 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Coburn, Alvin F., 1973 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Cockrell, Janice L., 1981 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Cole, Jonathan R., 1981 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Cole, Roger, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Colebrook, Vera, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Coons, Albert H., 1970 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Creighton, Donald J., 1978 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Crovley, Nuala, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Crumrine, Martin H., 1975 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Curnen, Edward, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Cushing, Alice H., 1971 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Central Public Health Laboratory, London, 1949-1972 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Communicable Disease Center, Georgia, 1949-1962 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Communicable Disease Center [name changed to Center for Disease Control on stationery], 1963-1975 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Dahl, Lewis K., 1953 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - D'Alessandro, Giuseppe, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Dangler, Gertrude, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Data, Helen, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Delafield, Frederick, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - DeLameter, Edward D., 1949-1951 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - deMello, Gilbert C., 1952-1958 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Denny, Floyd, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Derick, C.L., 1958 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Deuschle, Kurt W., 1958 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Dhanda, M.R., 1959 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Difco Laboratories, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Downs, Cora M., 1949 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - DuBois, Robert O., 1958 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Dunham, Wolcott B., 1949 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Dunlap, Marjorie B., 1956-1959 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Dunn, M.S., 1947 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Dunning, Harold, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Duran-Reynals, F., 1952-1956 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Delisle, Allan L., 1969 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Dillon, Hugh C., 1966-1979 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Dingle, John H., 1965 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Downie, A.W., 1972 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Dubos, René, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Duncan, James L., 1978 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Dunkle, Lisa M., 1978 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Eagle, Harry, 1940-1950 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Eastern Airlines, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Ederer, Grace Mary, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Edge, Cary O., 1947 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Edwards, P.R., 1947-1948 1959 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Eisenhart, Marvin A., 1966 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Eisenstein, Roby K., 1975 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Eisman, P.C., 1947 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Ekstedt, Richard D., 1957 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Ellen, Richard P., 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Elliott, Stuart, 1947-1979 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Ellis, Robert J., 1964 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Emmart, Emily W., 1956 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Engel, H.W.B., 1978 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Entine, Martin, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Erickson, E.D., 1971 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Erlandson, Arvid L., 1973 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Ernest, Helen, 1958-1959 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Esseireld, H., 1957 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Everly, William ("Bill"), 1971 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Feldman, Harry A., 1950-1959 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Fellman, Jean, 1948-1949 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Felsen, Joseph, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Fifield, Charles W., 1953 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Finland, Maxwell, 1949-1950 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Fisher, Elizabeth G., 1948 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Foley, Marie Judith, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Forbes, Martin, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Forkner, Claude, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Forster, George F., 1947-1948 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Foter, Milton J., 1947 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Fox, Eugene N., 1950 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Fox, Noah, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Freedman, Dorothy, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Friou, George J., 1947-1955 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Fry, Ronald M., 1959 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Fuerst, H.T., 1948-1949 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Facklam, Richard C., 1971 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Falcoff, Ernest T., 1959-1960 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Fauve, Robert M., 1962 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Fasan, Dorcas M., 1960 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Feigin, Ralph D., 1974 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Feldman, Harry A., 1960-1974 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Feldman, William E., 1979 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Fenton, Lawrence J., 1975-1977 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - deFerreira Crespo, C., 1970 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Ferrieri, Patricia, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Few, C., 1970 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Finch, Stuart C., 1970 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Finland, Maxwell, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Finn, Pamela D., 1970 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Fleming, Diane O., 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Florell, Cirl, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Foley, Marie Judith, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Forsum, Urban, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Fox, Eugene N., 1976 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Fox, Hazel M., 1971 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Freimer, Earl H., 1970 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Fry, R.M., 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Galiana, Joaquin, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Gallaher, M.A., 1947 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Gaughran, Eugene R.L., 1951 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Gezon, Horace, 1947-1950 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Gillespie, J.H., 1949 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Ginsburg, I., 1959 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Girvin, Grace T., 1953 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Glaser, Robert J., 1955-1960 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Glaubiger, Albert, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Goldberg, S.A., 1947 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Goldin, Milton, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Gooder, Harry, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Goodman, Neville M., 1947 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Gordon, John E., 1960 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Gordon, Ruth, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Graef, Irving, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Greenblatt, I., 1948 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Grey, Howard, 1959-1960 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Grichener, Ernesto, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Gale, E.F., 1968 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Gall, Lorraine S., 1965 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Galvan, Manuel de J., 1966-1967 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Genco, Robert J., 1969 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Gerhardt, Philipp, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Gershman, Melvin, 1963 1967 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Gezon, Horace M., 1966 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Gibbons, William E., 1978 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Gilad, Varda, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Gilbertson, Edna, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Glaser, Robert J., 1961 1963 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Glaudemans, C.P.J., 1979 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Goldhaber, Gertrude S., 1973-1975 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Gooder, Harry, 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Gotoff, Samuel P., 1976 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Granovetter, David A., 1978 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Greene, Hazel, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Greenwald, James, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Grichener, Ernesto, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Gross, Stanley, 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Gump, Dieter W., 1963 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Gunsalus, I.C., 1964 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Gupta, B.R., 1970 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Gupta, Ras B., 1965 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Hackenthal, Dr., 1951-1952 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Hadley, Philip, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Halbert, Seymour P., 1951 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Hansen, P. Arne, 1951 1955 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Harris, Albert H., 1953 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Harris, Susanna, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Harris, T.N., 1956 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Hartman, Thomas L., 1947-1948 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Havas, H. Francis, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Hayano, S., 1957 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Hedlund, Per, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Heins, William A., 1948 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Henderson, David W., 1954 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Hevitt, L.F., 1949-1952 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Hill, Justina, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Himes, George E., 1951 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Hirch, Ann, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Hobby, Gladys, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Hodge, Ben, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Hogan, Michael J., 1948 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Holbrook, W. Paul, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Holland, R.F., 1956 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Hollinger, Nell, 1949 1952 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Holm, August, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Holt, Rebecca, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Howell, J.D., 1948 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Hadley, Susan J., 1964 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Haffkine Institute, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Hahn, J.J., 1964 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Haight, James C., 1965 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Hamburger, Morton, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Hana, Ivo, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Harrell, W.H., 1964 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Harris, T.N., 1965 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Hayashi, James A., 1962 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Hayashi, Takayoshi, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Hedén, C.-G., 1958 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Heggie, John F., 1966 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Heidelberger, Michael, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Hertel, Dr., 1959 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Hijmans, W., 1959 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Hirst, George K., 1958 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Hollinger, Nell, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Holm, Stig E., 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Hook, E.W., 1958-1959 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Horstmann, Dorothy M., 1959 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Hotchkiss, Paul, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Hurst, Valerie, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Hutchison, Dorris J., 1959 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Hall, Robert T., 1974 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Hall, Shelby, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Hamada, Shigeyuki, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Handley, H.H., 1980 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Harr, Ronald, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Harrell, William K., 1967 1971 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Harrison, Carla, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Haug, Rangdi Holth, 1971-1973 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Hayashi, Takayoshi T.A., 1977 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Hayward, John, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Health, Education, and Welfare, Department of, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Heymer, Berno, 1972-1976 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Hijmans, W., 1967 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Hill, Harry R., 1976 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Hirschhorn, Rochelle, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Hobby, Gladys, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Hokama, Y., 1975 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Holloway, William, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Holm, Stig E., 1976 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Housewright, Riley D., 1972 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Immunological Methods, Journal of, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Immunologists, American Association of, 1962-1965 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Iragorry, L. Briceno, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Iverson, Wendell G., 1972 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - International Bacteriological Nomenclature Committee. Subcommittee on Streptococci and Pneumococci, circa 1951-1962 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - International Bacteriological Nomenclature Committee. Subcommittee on Streptococci and Pneumococci, circa 1963-1975 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Jablon, James M., 1960-1962 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Jackson, Robert W., 1966-1967 1976 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Jacobs, M.R., 1974 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Jacobs, N.J., 1963 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Jacok, Ralph F., 1949 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Jaconia, Don, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - James, John A., 1961 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Jelinkova, Jarmila, 1970-1975 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Jeljaszewicz, J., 1956-1970 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Jeter, Wayburn S., 1949 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Johnson, Gary R., 1965 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Johnson, Jennifer C., 1968 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Johnson, R.B., 1949 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Johnson, William, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Joiner, Marjorie, 1948-1950 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Joseph, S.W., 1963 1966 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Judis, Joseph, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Kalbak, K., 1949 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Kaminsky, Daniel, 1956 or 1957 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Kaplan, Melvin H., 1954 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Kaufmann, W., 1948 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Keogh, E.V., 1953 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Kidwell, Elizabeth Willcox, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Kilbourne, Edwin D., 1952 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Kingston, J.R. Kirby, Margaret M., 1949 1951 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Kirschner, L., 1948-1957 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Köhler, Werner, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Kohlstaedt, Kenneth G., 1947 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Krasner, Robert I., 1958 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Kraus, Frederick W., 1949-1952 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Krause, Richard, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Kristensen, Martin, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Krueger, Lois, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Kudo, S., 1954-1955 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Kuhn, L. Roland, 1948-1950 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Kupferberg, Alfred B., 1952 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Kuroya, Masahiko, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Kusama, Hideyo, 1957-1958 (Box 5, Folder 10)